thanks to curiosity stream for
supporting PBS Digital Studios
hey um Jabril and welcome to crash
course AI and the supervised learning
episode we taught John Green bot to
learn using a perceptron a program that
imitates one neuron but our brains make
decisions with a hundred billion neurons
which have trillions of connections
between them we can actually do a lot
more with AI if we connect a bunch of
perceptrons together to create what's
called an artificial neural network
neuro networks are better than other
methods for certain tasks like image
recognition the secret to their success
is their hidden layers and they're
mathematically very elegant
both of these are reasons why neural
networks are one of the most dominant
machine learning technologies used today
not that long ago a bit challenging AI
was real world image recognition like
recognizing a dog from a cat and the car
from the plane from a boat even though
we do it every day
it's really hard for computers that's
because computers are good at literal
comparisons like matching zeros and ones
one at a time it's easy for computers to
tell that these images are the same by
matching the pixels but before AI a
computer couldn't tell that all of these
images are of the same dog and had no
hope of telling that all of these
different images are dogs so if a
freshman named Fei Fei Lee and a group
of other machine learning and computer
vision researchers wanted to help the
research community develop AI that could
recognize images the first step was to
create a huge public data set of labeled
real-world photos that way computer
scientists around the world who come up
with and test different algorithms they
called this data set image net it had
3.2 million labeled images sorted into
five thousand two hundred and forty
seven nested categories of nouns like
for example the dog label is nested
under domestic animal which is nested
under animal humans are the best
I rely ibly labeling data but if one
person did all this labeling taking ten
seconds per label without any sleep or
snack breaks it would take them over a
year so image Ned used crowdsourcing and
leverage the power of the Internet to
cheaply spread the work between
thousands of people once the data was in
place the researchers started an annual
competition in 2010 to get people to
contribute their best solutions to image
recognition enter Alex Khrushchev Sookie
who was a graduate student at the
University of Toronto in 2012 he decided
to apply a neural network to image net
even though similar solutions hadn't
been successful in the past his neuro
network called Alex net had a couple of
innovations that set it apart he used a
lot of hidden layers which we'll get
into in a minute he also used faster
computation hardware to handle all the
math that neural networks do alex net
outperformed the next best approaches by
over ten percent it only got three out
of 20 images wrong in great terms it was
getting a solid B while other techniques
were scraping
by loc since 2012 no networks have taken
over the annual competition and the
results keep getting better and better
plus Alex net sparked an explosion of
research into neuro networks which we
start to apply to lots of things beyond
image recognition to understand how
neural networks can be used for these
classification problems we have to
understand the architecture first all
neural networks are made up of an input
layer and output layer and any number of
hidden layers in between there are many
different arrangements but we'll use the
classic multi-layer perceptron as an
example the input layer is where the
neural network receives data represented
as numbers each input neuron represents
a single feature which is some
characteristic of the data features are
straightforward if you're talking about
something that's already a number like
grams of sugar and in donut but really
just about anything can be converted
into a number sounds can be represented
as the amplitudes of the sound wave so
each feature would have a number that
represents the amplitude at a moment in
time words in the paragraph can be
represented by how many times each word
appears so each feature would have the
frequency of one word or if we're trying
to label an image of a dog each feature
would represent information about a
pixel so for a grayscale image each
feature would have a number representing
how bright a pixel is but for a color
image we can represent each pixel with
three numbers the amount of red green
and blue which can be combined to make
any color on your computer screen once
the features have data each one sends
its number to every neuron in the next
layer called the hidden layer then each
hidden layer neuron mathematically
combines all the numbers it gets the
goal is to measure whether the input
data has certain components for an image
recognition problem these components may
be a certain color in the center a curve
near the top or even whether the image
contains eyes ears or fur instead of
answering yes or no like the simple
perception from the previous episode
each neuron in the hidden layer does
some slightly more complicated math and
outputs a number and then each neuron
sends its number to every neuron in the
next layer which could be another hidden
layer or the output layer the output
layer is where the
final hidden layer outputs are
mathematically combined to answer the
problem so let's say we're trying to
label an image as a dog we might have a
single output neuron representing a
single answer that the image is of a dog
or not but if there are many answers
like for example if we're labeling a
bunch of images we'll need a lot of
output neurons each output neuron will
correspond to the probability for each
label like for example dog or spaghetti
and more and then we pick the answer
with the highest probability the key to
neural networks and really all of AI is
math and I get it a neuro network kind
of seems like a black box and does math
and spits out an answer I mean those
middle layers are even called hidden
layers but we can understand that gist
of what's happening by working through
an example Oh John Green bot let's give
John Green bot a program with a neural
network that's been trained to recognize
a dog in a grayscale photo when we show
him this photo first each feature will
contain a number between 0 and 1
corresponding to the brightness of one
pixel and it'll pass this information to
the hidden layer now let's focus on one
hidden layer neuron since the neural
network is already trained this neuron
has a mathematical formula to look at a
particular component in the image like a
specific curve in the center the curve
at the top of the nose if this neuron is
focused on this specific shape or spot
it may not really care what's happening
anywhere else so it would multiply or
weigh the pixel values from most of
these features by zero or close to zero
because it's looking for bright pixels
here it wouldn't multiply these pixel
values by a positive weight this curve
is also defined by a darker part below
so the neuron will multiply these pixel
values by a negative weight this hidden
neuron will add all the weighted pixel
values from the input neurons and squish
the results so that it's between 0 and 1
the final number basically represents
the guess of this neuron thinking that a
specific curve aka a dog knows
appeared in the image other hidden
neurons are looking for other components
like for example a different curve in
another part of the image or a fuzzy
texture when all of these neurons pass
their estimate on to the next hidden
layer those neurons may be trained to
look for more complex components like
one hidden neuron may check whether
there's a shape that might be a dog nose
it probably doesn't care about data from
previous layers that look for furry
textures so it wastes those by zero or
close to zero but it may really care
about neurons that looks for the top of
the nose and the bottom of the nose and
nostrils it ways those by large positive
numbers again it would add up all the
weighted values from the previous layer
neurons squish the value between 0 and 1
and pass this to the next layer that's
the gist of the math but we're
simplifying it a bit it's important to
know that neural networks don't actually
understand ideas like nose or eyelid
each neuron is doing a calculation on
the data it's given and just flagging
specific patterns of light and dark
after a few more hidden layers we reach
the output layer with one neuron so
after one more weighted addition of the
previous layers data which happens in
the output neuron the network shall have
a good estimate if this image is a dog
which means John Green bot should have a
decision
93% hey John Green bot nice job
thinking about how no networks would
process just one image makes it clear
why AI needs fast computers like I
mentioned before each pixel in a color
image would be represented by three
numbers how much red green and blue it
has so to process 8,000 by a thousand
pixel image which in comparison is a
small 3x3 inch photo a neural network
needs to look at three million features
Alex net needed more than 60 million
neurons to achieve this which is a ton
of math and could take a lot of time to
compute which is something we should
keep in mind when designing neural
networks to solve problems people are
really excited about using deeper neural
networks which are networks with more
hidden layers to do deep learning deep
networks can combine input data in more
complex ways to look for more complex
components and solve trickier problems
but we can't make all networks like a
billion layers deep because more hidden
layers means more math which again would
mean that we need faster computers plus
as a network gets deeper it gets harder
for us to make sense of why it's giving
us the answers that it does each neuron
and the first hidden layer is looking
for some specific component of the input
data but in deeper layers those
components get more abstract from how
humans would describe the same data now
this may not seem like a big deal but if
a new network was used to deny our loan
request for example we want to know why
which features made the difference and
how are they weighted towards the final
answer in many countries we have the
legal right to understand why these kind
of decisions were made and neural
networks are being used to make more in
more decisions about our lives most
banks for example use no networks to
detect and prevent fraud many cancer
tests like the Pap tests for cervical
cancer use a neural network to look at
an image of cells under a microscope and
decide whether there's a risk of cancer
and neural networks or how alexa
understands what song you're asking to
play and our facebook suggests tags for
our photos understanding how all this
happens is really important to being a
human in the world right now whether or
not you want to build your own neural
network so this was a lot of big-picture
stuff but the program we gave John Green
by
had already been trained to recognize
dogs the neurons already had algorithms
that weighted inputs next time we'll
talk about the learning process used by
neural networks to get the right weights
for every neuron and why they need so
much data to work well thank you to
curiosity stream for supporting PBS
Digital Studios curiosity stream is a
subscription streaming service that
offers documentaries and nonfiction
titles from a variety of filmmakers
including curiosity stream originals for
example you can stream a curious world
which over two seasons of episodes
answers questions like can we colonize
Mars and could robots rule the world you
can learn more at curiosity stream comm
slash crash course or click the link in
the description crash course AI is
produced in association with PBS Digital
Studios if you want to help keep crash
course free for everyone forever you can
join our community on patreon and if you
don't learn more about the math behind
neural networks check out this video
from crash course statistics about them
[Music]